Are you gonna tell me how you're involved?
I wasn't involved.
Did they...
Our best guess is
they abducted him for some reason.
Okay. so shouldn't you be out there
chasing after them?
Or at the crime scene or something?
I've got two entire squads doing that.
Right now.
my only job is to sit at this table
till you tell me
what you're doing here. Zara.
He. he called me up.
[sniffles]
He was babbling. Distraught.
So. I told him I would come over
and see if he was okay.
And then when I got there.
I saw the blood in the lift...
and I. I just had to get out.
Of a window?
The. the men at the door. the cops.
I thought they were the kidnappers.
So. yesterday. during the robbery.
you took the call and saved the day.
And tonight. you're at it again.
helping out.
You and Luke must be pretty tight then.
you rushing through the night for him.
Yeah. we are.
So. he tells you everything?
He didn't tell me
he was gonna get kidnapped.
- What about the heist?
- No.
- Did he offer you a share?
- [scoffs] No!
So. your best mate had a £4 billion payday
and he didn't think to cut you in?
[sighs]
You see anyone
when you were inside the building?
Anything might make the difference
between us saving Luke... or not.
It's not just him.
If they saw you.
you're in just as much danger.
Okay.
Someone will call you tomorrow
to take your statement.
[camera shutter clicking]
[Ellie] It wasn't your fault.
you know. Rhys.
It was the surveillance team
that fucked up.
[camera shutter clicking]
Where were you when Luke called?
Why are you asking?
Because I'm your mate?
What about Zara?
Did you get a read on her?
Yeah. she's involved.
We've got enough to arrest her.
Not yet.
Let's put her under surveillance.
I'll gather some background info.
You go get a statement from her.
We can cross-check it
with the team who were watching Luke.
[Ellie] Could be she's involved.
Or she's just an office worker
whose life is so pointless
she has to get wasted every weekend
just to bear it.
[camera shutter clicks]
[lock clicks]
[sniffles]
[upbeat hip-hop music playing
over speakers]
[Zara] Where's Wayne and Chee?
They went to. er...
Oh. nice.
I'm so hungry.
Zara. do they not piss you off?
Who?
The Investment Committee dickheads.
[Zara] They're not all dickheads.
- Milo's all right...
- They're on a million quid a year. basic
with 100% guaranteed bonus.
- Hmm?
- What the fuck do they do for it?
They're getting rich off our work.
- No. that's not true. They...
- Meanwhile. meanwhile.
we're sitting there.
processing all their bullshit trades.
and what do we get for it?
[Wayne] Chips?
We're supposed to be getting drunk.
- [Chioma] Aw. boo!
- Ah. ah. ah. ah.
Eating's cheating. Zara.
Especially when. you know.
the woo-woo train is at the station.
[Zara] 100 grand?
- [Luke] Yeah.
- [Zara] And where did you meet them?
Like. online.
Where online?
Playing Call of Duty.
- Oh. you gotta... Okay.
- Okay. yes. I know.
Some people you've never met.
who just happened to be playing
the same online game as you.
just happened to mention
that they're interested
in hacking a pension fund.
which you just happen to work for?
It's 100 grand.
- You are being groomed. my love.
- Listen. they said.
they said they need two of us.
which is why I'm asking you.
Do you want in? Yes or no?
No. I am not going to jail for 50 grand.
No. No. no. no. It's 100 grand.
It's 100 grand each. okay?
And you're not gonna go to jail.
because all they wanna do
is just get some info
to hack our accounts.
Right? And they didn't just
want any accounts.
They asked for our worst account.
So who do you think I said?
- Washington Tobacco.
- Okay.
Right. they're just gonna
hit their executive pot.
All right. course. So. we're basically
saving people from cancer.
Think what we can do with 100 grand.
[Zara gasps]
Coke and video games?
I'm in debt.
To who?
- To credit card companies. to...
- [Zara sighs]
- To financial institutions. Banks!
- Okay. All right.
- I. I'm fucked!
- Okay. calm down!
- I am fucked!
- Calm down.
I'm fucked. Zara. Please.
They said they're only gonna do it
with two people. I'm begging you.
I. I. need this.
Okay. but why would they need two of us
to give them the same info?
I don't know. they.
something to do with the verification.
- hacking the log-in system...
- Well. that's what's
- even fucking dodgier. Luke.
- Sure.
There's no way that we're gonna...
- [knocking at door]
- [man] Come on. hurry up!
Yeah. Hold on.
[dance music playing over speakers]
- [meat sizzling]
- [man] Er. no. no.
I just like onions with mine.
Oh. God.
Why do we do this every weekend?
[Luke] It's 100 grand!
We... we fucking deserve it.
Look into your future 30 years from now.
doing the same mind-numbing shit.
reading the same fucking spreadsheets
and all the while. the traders
are getting younger and younger
and making more in a year
than we are ever gonna see
in our entire lives.
And all the while. that buzzing sound
in the back of your head. yeah?
You hear it? That little mosquito
getting louder and louder?
That is your fucking life.
You fucking wasted it.
So. wait. d'you know what
you're gonna turn out like?
- Your mum. And...
- Fuck you!
No. you know what? Fuck you!
I'm going in on Monday.
I'm gonna change teams.
I'm gonna get put on track
for an investment role.
You can process trades
on your fucking own.
[Luke] That's never gonna work. Zara!
You said it yourself.
They'll laugh you out the room.
What. 'cause I'm. I'm such a joke. am I?
No. because they don't see what I see.
Okay? They just see a girl
in a crumpled suit
with a psychology degree
from a second-rate uni
who has never. ever shown any ambition.
And that's not gonna change. Zara.
Not for them.
We'll see.
[inaudible]
[Luke] Well?
Well. they said...
I'm an exceptional worker with...
an outstanding eye for detail.
a meticulous approach
to the paperwork and a...
rare gift for the numerate side
of the job.
- And...
- [typing]
it's for those reasons
they think I'm best suited
to a continued role in the back office.
Yeah.
[Zara sighs]
[whispering] One condition.
I don't wanna do this over your...
PlayStation. okay?
If I'm gonna get involved in...
whatever this is.
I wanna meet them.
In person. Otherwise.
I'm not getting involved.
[Luke] Deal.
[sniffles]
MI5? Are you serious?
It's in their remit.
And it's just one analyst. A liaison.
- Thanks for the heads-up.
- Yesterday. you were worried
we were moving too slowly.
today. we're going too fast?
This surveillance request for...
Zara Dunne.
She's Luke Selborn's work wife.
I think she's involved.
Right. well. put in the paperwork.
I'll see what I can do.
Here he is.
You never know.
Might be fun to have
an actual spy in the office.
DCI Covaci? Sam Fitch.
- Rhys is fine. Pleased to meet you.
- You. too.
Look. I. er. just wanted to say.
straight off the bat.
I'm not here to step on any toes.
I'm a resource. I've got a line
straight back to Thames House.
all the tech and expertise
we've got there.
But only if you want it.
That's great. Thank you.
Er. we'll introduce you to the team
- and. er. Ellie can show you around.
- Sure.
Everyone. Listen up.
This is Sam Fitch.
from the security services.
He's gonna be in the office. helping out.
It's not every day
they get introduced to a spy.
[chuckles]
Er. spy is not really the right word.
- I'm an intelligence officer. which is...
- [mobile phone buzzing]
basically just
a glorified civil servant.
- Kinda like you lot.
- [scattered laughter]
Hey. Welcome to Crime Scene Pro.
Today. we're gonna show you
how experts copy fingerprints
that have been left in blood.
It's a different process to lifting
regular fingerprints
and you can still get it done with
just a few everyday household items.
Here's how.
Twenty grand.
Congratulations.
I want the rest in a week
or I'm selling your loan.
- Selling it to who?
- [tuts]
To "whom". Fuck's sake.
To people who don't care what your job is.
- [scoffs] Come on. Matt. I...
- No.
I've tried to be a mate about this.
One week. and then I wash my hands of it.
And you can take your chances
with the kind of people
who buy these kinds of debts.
See you in a week. I guess.
[lift beeping]
[doors opening]
Yeah.
It's Covaci.
- What have you got?
- Er...
I'm still waiting for access
to some of their shared drives.
but everything I've seen so far
is by the book.
What about people of interest?
Anyone in debt? Or suddenly flush?
I've been going through
some of their personal bank accounts.
Er. Luke Selborn has... [inhales deeply]
got seven of them.
All overdrawn.
No unusual transactions. though.
What about Zara?
Low balance but clean as a whistle.
Same as all the other back-office staff
and the Investment Committee.
Which makes sense.
considering the amount they're paid.
- [Rhys] How much?
- They could earn a million a year
in basic.
Same again in bonuses.
The ones there. in the bullpen.
Zara and Luke's bit.
30. 40 grand annual.
Which means it takes them three decades
to earn what their colleagues take home
in a year.
Double that. if you include the bonuses.
How's it going with the stolen money?
Our British Virgin Island request
is still in the queue.
Do you have any idea what's going on?
[pen thuds on table]
[softly] So I was... I was thinking...
maybe we could bypass them.
Go on.
Okay. so you know there's been
all these leaks over the years.
- Pandora Papers. Panama Papers...
- Hmm.
Well. there are these databases online
where all the leaked
offshore account details are.
I could cross-check our accounts
with the ones online.
see if anything pings.
We couldn't use it as evidence.
No. but it would mean
we're not just waiting around.
[clears throat]
Which type were you
when you worked in the City?
Investment Committee or back office?
Investment Committee.
Part of why I quit.
The massive wages?
[laughs]
I prefer what I do now. Rhys.
Means I can look at myself in the mirror.
[sighs]
Do it.
What you suggested.
But not here.
I'm officially approving your request
to work from home this afternoon.
Hi...
Thank you.
[Ellie] Zara?
DI Ellie Lloyd. We met the other day?
I'm just here to take your statement
about last night.
This is my colleague. Sam Fitch.
I thought you were gonna call.
[Ellie] We're calling now.
Well. no. I meant on the phone.
to arrange coming over.
Have we caught you at a bad time?
No.
No. no. I just. erm.
flat's in a bit of a state
and I haven't really... slept.
so. maybe we can do this some other time?
No. Now's good.
Cool.
Can I. erm. get you a drink or anything?
[Ellie] No. nothing. thanks.
- Shall we sit down and take the statement?
- [Zara] Yeah.
[Ellie] Thanks.
[knock at door]
[Rhys] Thanks for taking the time.
[Haley] Please...
I wasn't sure I'd find you at home.
Well. I'm. um... a psychiatric nurse.
- Twelve hours on. twelve hours off.
- Yeah.
Er. it's not my preferred line of work
but. you know. I was in a bind. so...
[smacks lips]
So. you think
my daughter stole £4 billion?
Not exactly.
Right. So why are you here?
Does she ever talk to you about her work?
No. Hang on.
Why are you here?
Oh. erm. I'm trying to look for...
Listen! Why are you here?
I'm not gonna say anything
until you give me a context.
I'm worried about her.
She's mixed up with some dangerous people.
Right.
So. you're her knight in shining armour
come to save her?
[inhales deeply and exhales]
Well...
watch out. DCI Covaci.
You've got no idea
what you're getting involved with.
The jaded office worker stumbling
through life.
that's just her pretending
she chose it all.
like it's not eating her up inside.
It's a very dangerous combination.
You know?
Intelligence and frustration.
You asked me if my daughter
could have been involved in a heist?
Well. I wouldn't be surprised
if she masterminded
the whole bloody thing.
If she set her mind to it.
Problem is. she never
sets her mind to anything.
Too scared.
Wants everything to be settled and...
calm and safe.
And why is that?
How else would she be
with a mother like me?
You wanna know something about Zara?
Go on.
You're exactly her type.
Go on. Ask me something else.
Has she been acting differently recently?
I wouldn't know.
[sighs] She broke off all contact
a few months ago.
You're estranged?
When was the last time you saw her?
Mrs Dunne?
[sighs]
I haven't seen her in months.
And then I saw all the blood and I just.
I just knew I had to get out of there.
So. because we were worried
about Luke's safety.
we had a couple of our colleagues
outside of his building. keeping a log...
- Okay.
- Of everyone entering and leaving.
And I went through their logs
and the CCTV
from the building opposite Luke's.
Well. all that suggests
that you were in the building for...
ten minutes.
But from what you've just told me here.
it sounds like you were in there
significantly less.
Do you have any idea why that might be?
No. I mean. I'm not particularly good
with timings
and. and as I said.
I haven't really slept. so...
And when you arrived.
you had your hood up?
It was cold. [chuckles]
- Really?
- Yeah.
It was quite mild. I thought. No?
[Fitch] Fifteen degrees.
[Ellie] And the cab
that you claimed you got there.
it's not on CCTV.
There's just a shot of you walking in.
with your hood up.
Oh. well. it... The cab did drop me.
erm. off further down the street.
And the cabbie. he said something about.
like. a one-way system or something.
[Ellie] Zara?
Are you sure you wanna submit this
as your statement?
Because once you sign it. that's it.
it's part of your record
and lawyers can use it in court.
Er. no. yeah. it's fine.
Okay.
Well. have a read through it all
and then sign and date this at the bottom.
Thank you.
Erm. have...
You haven't heard anything
about Luke at all. have you?
No. not yet.
but we've got an entire unit
looking for him.
[softly] Okay.
We're checking number plate data.
honing in on the vehicles.
so... we'll find him.
And we'll find the people that did it.
- Great.
- Promise.
[Zara] Thank you. [clears throat]
My God. She's so fucking guilty.
I'll write up a report
and send it to Nichols.
We need to get her
under surveillance ASAP.
I'm not so sure.
- Not sure about what?
- The surveillance request.
Are you serious?
Look. maybe she's involved.
but she's not the angle here.
The angle's finding Luke.
It's tracking the money.
She's a bit part. at best.
We've got our inside man.
That's who we focus on.
- So. the surveillance request?
- We don't need it.
I'll speak to Nichols. He'll understand.
- [London] Luke and Zara?
- [both] Yes.
So. this is just a get-to-know-you
meeting. all right?
- You got drinks?
- Er. yeah.
[London] We'll get some.
and then we can have a chat. All right?
Cool. And that's good with me.
And just so. like I said in the messages.
it's mainly Zara that needed convincing.
I'm good with whatever...
Basically. you can trust me.
is what I'm trying to say.
[chuckles] Let's get some drinks. eh?
We'll. erm. just see you over there.
[Glasses] It's just an hour-long chat.
where you tell us
how your trading system works.
give us your account details.
log-in details.
Just an hour of your life chatting.
For more money
than you'll earn in two years.
[Glasses] No one's gonna know
you had anything to do with it.
No one's going to get hurt. And the money.
we take it from the tobacco execs.
like we said.
Yeah.
Look. there's no need to make a decision
now. This isn't a hard sell.
Just have a think about it
and let us know. Okay?
Any questions?
[scoffs] Yeah.
Why aren't you guys wearing masks
or disguises or anything?
[chuckling] I mean.
you're about to do this big crime.
and you've just shown
a pair of strangers your faces.
It kinda suggests that...
What? We're a bunch of amateurs?
No. no. That it doesn't really matter.
because after the hack.
you're gonna kill us.
[both chuckle]
Look.
the point of this meeting was to get
to know each other. build some trust.
We couldn't do that
if we'd turned up in disguises. could we?
Yeah.
[Glasses] This is gonna be
a victimless crime.
Like I said. no one's gonna get hurt.
Especially not one of us.
- I promise you.
- Er. is this why they brought you along?
To provide the female reassurance?
[laughs]
Like I said. have a think.
And in the meantime.
it's probably best if we leave one by one.
[Zara sighs] Okay.
[Zara grunts]
- [driver] Evening. Hackney. right?
- Hiya. Yeah.
Wait. Do you see that car behind us?
When it moves. can you follow it?
The app says Greenarch Street. Hackney.
Yeah. well. I've changed my mind.
Can you follow that car. please?
I can't just drive around all night.
I need a destination for the app.
Okay. well. fine. I will cancel the trip
and I'll give you 50 quid cash.
Is that okay?
I could earn more booking this.
[Zara] Please.
Look. he's leaving. Can you...
[driver] Jesus! All right.
So. what is he? Your boyfriend?
Yeah.
Just. er... just stop here.
Okay. You can. you can go.
So...
these accounts are where
the money's been sent.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
Gould-Simmons? The Gould-Simmons?
Yeah. well. I mean. like.
it's a shell company
in a holding company. in a shell company.
if that makes sense.
but yeah. I'm pretty sure.
Someone stole £4 billion worth of pensions
and sent it to the offshore accounts
of an arms dealer?
They're not an arms dealer. Rhys.
They're a defence contractor.
Every one of our fighter jets.
missile systems...
Yeah. Right. So. why would they take money
from a heist?
You don't think that maybe
whoever is behind this
might be using the money to buy arms?
You're buying arms under the table.
you don't go to a household name
with money that's all over the news.
Okay. Well. then what?
Someone's just using their accounts?
Yeah. but why?
Why use their accounts?
Why not set up your own?
And why the fuck
have Gould-Simmons got accounts
in some no-name bank
in the British Virgin Islands?
My guess... [sighs] would be.
these are the kinds of accounts
you use to pay bribes.
Slush fund accounts?
Well. er. except slush fund accounts
you use to pay money out.
- This. er...
- This money is moving the wrong way.
- Yeah.
- What do we do with this?
Well. we. er.
we take it upstairs or we sit on it.
We take it upstairs. they'll sit on it.
Yeah. well. it's gonna get out there
sooner or later.
So. what?
Maybe we leak it ourselves?
[chuckles]
[grunts] I don't know. Rhys.
You think MI5 know about this?
MI5?
They planted an agent
in the incident room this morning.
[Darren sighs]
Rhys. I... [chuckles]
I found this out via an open source.
online database.
Think about the tools MI5 have.
They probably knew
ten minutes after the heist.
[sighs]
[woman] ..which is why
here at Gould-Simmons.
we're upgrading Britain's rapid
response capability with state-of...
We need to talk.
Fitch came with me
to take Zara Dunne's statement.
She's totally involved. Rhys.
I could see it. Fitch could see it.
She could see it.
But we get outside.
and Fitch says.
"She's probably not involved."
And he's going to talk to Nichols about
turning down our surveillance request.
- Have you spoken to Nichols?
- No. I was waiting for you.
Whatever Fitch is up to.
Nichols is involved too. no?
They don't want us going near her.
He basically told me. "She's off-limits."
- Fitch definitely knew she was lying?
- Yeah.
And then he pretended she wasn't.
but it was fucking blatant.
What are we gonna do?
Act like everything's cool.
I'll take care of it.
[indistinct chatter]
[Deuchart] Can I help you?
What are you doing here?
It's evidence. on the desk.
I could have given it to the cops.
but I brought it here to you.
How did you get this address?
I just wanted to come here
and tell you that you can trust me.
I'm not going to make any trouble.
like Luke...
[shouts] I said how did you
get this address?
I promise...
[panting and grunting]
[indistinct chatter]
[exhales]
[door creaking]
[beep]
[panting]
[exhales]
[breathing heavily]
[ringing tone]
- Hey. Mum.
- [Haley] Yeah? What's up?
I was. er. I was just thinking
about popping over.
Oh. my dear. I'm on a night shift tonight.
Or maybe... maybe tomorrow?
Yeah. Come round tomorrow.
I'll be home tomorrow.
All right. See you.
Bye. love.
[chuckles]
[Rhys] Is my investigation
being set up to fail?
Why?
If someone's pressuring you...
[Nichols] They aren't pressuring me.
They're threatening me.
Rhys.
if you want to carry on
being a policeman when this is all over.
find a reason
to excuse yourself from the case
that doesn't point suspicion my way.
then step away.
I cannot guarantee
that whoever is in charge of this case
will come out of it in one piece.
Especially someone like you.
Someone like me?
A man with debts.
- Is this why I was picked for this?
- [Nichols scoffs]
To be the fall guy?
Don't be so bloody paranoid.
But your...
problem...
will come out in the wash.
Resign the case.
It's the only way
you're going to survive this.
[distant siren]
[keys jingling]
[door slams]
[Haley] Going somewhere?
[Zara exhales sharply]
Jesus. you scared the shit out of me.
I thought you were at work.
Yeah. and I thought
you were coming round tomorrow.
It's not up there any more.
[Zara sighs]
I'm not stupid. Zara.
Fuck's sake.
I haven't seen you in months.
and then you turn up out of the blue
the day after your company's been robbed?
It's funny to think
there's been four billion quid
stashed under my floorboards.
and I didn't have a clue.
It's not four billion.
Well. I looked up what a cold wallet is.
Spent all afternoon researching it.
So how much is on it?
Well. if you read up. then you would know
that you can't get into it
without my passwords.
It's worthless
without my passwords. actually.
Right. And your passwords
are worthless without the cold wallet.
So. here we are.
Okay.
[sighs]
What do you want?
What do you think I want?
Storage fees.
[exhales]
The people that I am dealing with.
I think... I think they want me dead.
- I don't know. they were chasing me and...
- Oh. you brought them here?
- Well. I was trying...
- Nice.
To do a deal with them.
Mum. please. please.
I need the cold wallet so I...
get out of the country.
I can't do it without the money.
so I need it. So please give it to me.
And then...
And then when it's all calmed down.
yes. I will sort you out.
Wow.
You've really bitten off
more than you can chew. haven't you?
[sighs] Look.
love. I give you that cold wallet.
you're off to Brazil
and I never see you again.
[whimpering and sniffling]
Ugh... [crying and laughing]
I don't fucking believe you.
[Zara chuckles]
Come on. How much is on it?
You can at least...
you can at least tell me that much.
A million. Depending on the exchange rate.
What. they steal. you know. four billion.
and they give you what. one million?
I don't think so.
- Come on. How much?
- Five. Five million.
[laughing] Five? Wow!
Oh. my maths was never my strong point.
but I would say for a very reasonable
20% storage fees...
- Oh. I...
- Come on. you give me one million.
You get to keep the other four million.
- Everybody's happy.
- Mum. you are not getting a million quid.
You're gonna end up blowing through it.
and we'll both end up arrested.
Oh. come on. darling. Look.
you've got to learn to trust me more.
What. because you have done so much
to earn my trust!
Ugh. don't fucking get
all high and mighty with me. Zara!
Just take a guess who the hospital
has all its pensions with.
You have stolen your own
fucking mother's pension!
So don't turn your fucking nose up at me.
You've been doing it since you were a kid.
and I'm fucking sick of it.
Yeah. you just... just go home.
calm down and then. you know.
give me a call in a few days
and we'll work something out. okay?
You don't get it. Mum.
After tonight.
I won't be alive in a few days.
[panting]
Get in!
- [engine revs]
- [tyres screeching]
Are you okay?
Thank you.
I feel like such a fucking idiot.
I was trying to reason with them.
Give them a peace offering.
- Fuck!
- Who's "them"?
[inhales and exhales]
The thieves.
[Zara breathing heavily]
Zara. that wasn't a thief
trying to pick you up back there.
Who else would it be?
It was MI5.